I know you don't smoke weed.
I know this.
But I'm gonna get you high today.
Because it's Friday.
You ain't got no job.
And you ain't got shit to do.
Dang, he at it again.
My daddy caught him trying to break
in to my house two days ago.
- And beat him down.
For real?
Mama.
Help.
Ha, you little rat bastards.
Gotta start the day off right, man.
Give me the two-piece special,
lots of hot sauce.
And all the fries you can give me.
Thank you.
For most people, Friday's just a day
before the weekend.
But after this Friday,
neighborhood will never be the same.
Shit.
- What's up?
- Good morning.
Are you prepared for Jehovah's return?
Because if you not,
I have a pamphlet here that...
Well, fuck you.
Half-dead motherfucker.
Come on, sister.
Dana.
- What?
- Do me a favor.
What, Craig?
Hook me up with Debbie.
No.
- Why not?
- Because she about to graduate.
She ain't got no time
to be messing with you.
Come on, Dana.
No.
Plus, Joi will kick your ass anyway.
Joi ain't gonna do a goddamn thing.
Craig, get out of my room.
Shut up.
You need to be up anyway.
- What time is it?
- 12:30.
For real?
Damn!
Yeah.
I got you.
I got you, baby.
All right.
Damn.
Ain't nothing in this house.
Shit.
Every time I come in the kitchen,
you in the kitchen...
...in the goddamn refrigerator...
...eating up all the food.
All the chicken.
All the pig feet.
You ate my dinner.
My mashed potatoes.
And the good old gravy I like,
the biscuits I like to sop that gravy.
You ate all that up.
You drink up the milk,
don't care what kind of milk it is.
You don't care, 2 percent,
3 percent, buttermilk.
Patent milk, pull the cow on
a patent milk can, I bet you eat that too.
What's wrong with you?
All I have is my grapes.
You gonna eat up all my grapes.
- Man...
- Now, when I went to bed last night...
...didn't I tell you to take out the trash?
Yeah.
So why didn't you do it?
- I fell asleep.
- I wish you was sleeping now.
I'd knock your head with a left hook...
...make your ass wake you up
and take out that damn trash.
Hey, hey, hey.
What are you doing?
I'm throwing this away.
We ain't even got no milk.
You better eat that damn cereal.
You ain't got no damn milk, goddamn bitch.
When I was coming up, we didn't have
milk, cereal, a bowl to eat in.
Spoon, fork and knife.
No napkins or nothing.
You do like this.
And put your hands like this.
- You ever do that?
- No.
Have you ever had government cheese?
- Craig, government cheese, you had some?
- No.
Big stinking government cheese.
Couldn't take a dump for two weeks.
Eat it on the 4th, by the 18th,
everybody trying to get to the bathrooms.
I wanna eat some of them chitlins,
I love pig feet.
The barbecue pig feet were gone.
You got grease all over your mouth.
I had a sweet potato pie,
you ate the pie.
Left me that little plastic thing there.
You ain't got no damn milk.
Ain't that a bitch?
You funny.
You're my boy.
You remind me of my granddaddy.
You know what your problem is?
You think money grows on trees.
Just go out, pick you 4 or $500 and go off
and just dance and eat chicken and dance.
You just having all the fun
in the world.
You know how many stinking dogs
I gotta catch...
...to fill that big ass bowl
you got there, boy?
Forty-five, 50 dogs.
Stinking, nasty dogs and 12 of them little
stinking things they call a chihuahua.
You better put some water
on that shit, boy.
All right, I'll eat it.
Hey, hey, hey.
Take the garbage out front, son.
What is wrong with him?
Hurry up with the garbage.
I got some more work for you.
What's up, Craig?
Don't "what's up" me.
I need to whoop your little ass
for knocking over these trash cans.
Don't knock these over.
Man, ain't nobody gonna knock over
your stupid trash cans.
You bet not.
Get that little bad ass in school anyway.
- Man, shut up, punk.
- What?
- I'm gonna knock over your trash cans.
- Better run.
Little bastard.
- Hey, Mama.
- Hi, baby.
- How you doing?
- Fine.
Oh, what you cooking?
I'm making some eggs, bacon, sausage,
pancakes, and some leftover pork chops.
Yeah.
Cook it up.
Mama, you got some glue?
- For what?
- My track slipped out.
- Go look in my dresser.
- You need a wig.
You need a job.
Hook.
Mom, you didn't tell Daddy
what happened yesterday, did you?
You know I wouldn't tell on my baby.
Cool.
Craig!
Huh?
Come in here.
Where you at?
In the bathroom.
I'll wait till you come out.
Bring your ass in here.
What you talking about?
I smelled your shit for 22 years,
now you can't smell mine for five minutes.
Shut the door.
Your mama told me
what happened to you yesterday.
- What?
- That was stupid.
How the hell you go get fired
on your day off?
I don't know.
Well, you need a trade.
Take a look at that paper over there
on the counter there.
I ain't trying to be no dog catcher.
Why not?
George Clinton was a dog catcher.
- No, he wasn't.
- Sure he was. That's why he said:
Do the dog catcher, dog catcher
I don't even like dogs.
That's the beauty of it.
I grab a dog...
...and I choke him,
and I kick the shit out of him...
...and I...
All day long, my foot up a dog's ass.
Just bang, bang, bang up his ass.
That's my pleasure.
I don't think so.
I'll tell you one thing.
Around here,
you gonna work or go to school.
The first of the month, rent is due.
If you ain't got nothing on the table,
you don't worry about catching a dog.
You gotta worry about a dog
catching your ass.
What's up?
Nothing.
Where's Debbie at?
Oh, she's at the house.
Craig, can I use y'all's microwave
right quick?
Yeah, what'd you gotta cook?
Some chicken.
- Give it here, I'll do it.
- No.
See, I was hoping that I could take it
to the house with me.
My microwave?
Yeah.
That's like me asking
to use your air condition.
You know,
if we had a air conditioner...
...I would let you use...
Craig.
- Damn.
Telephone.
- Hello.
- Who you go to the show with last night?
I didn't go to the show last night.
You ain't got to lie.
Craig, you ain't got to lie.
Ain't nobody lying.
I didn't go to the show.
Yes, you did. Because my sister-in-law's
baby cousin, Traci...
...she went to the show last night, she saw
you there all hugged up with some tramp.
Now tell me who she was.
Your sister-in-law's baby cousin, Traci,
is a goddamn...
Yeah, she a liar.
She ain't seen me at no movies
hugged up with nobody.
Yeah, yeah.
Well, let me tell you what.
You just tell the bitch, whoever she is,
when I catch her, I'm gonna beat her ass.
That girl gone.
I don't know why you messing
with that little fast-assed girl anyway.
Now that other girl, Debbie?
She's cute.
She's in school.
She has all her teeth.
I don't know what her sister's doing.
I'm trying to get with her,
but Dana won't even hook me up.
I told you to hook yourself up.
You need to hook up them clippers
and get the back of that neck.
Don't even talk
with all the horses missing their hair here.
- Oh. Here you go.
Hey, it's too early.
Now, Craig,
you know what your problem is?
You have no game.
What you know about game?
I got all the game.
Now, your father?
He got game.
Don't nobody go in the bathroom
for about 35, 45 minutes.
Somebody open a window.
You call that game?
There go my ride.
- Bye, Mommy.
- Bye-bye, honey.
- I gotta go.
- Bye, Daddy.
Bye-bye, baby.
Craig, you listen to me.
I want you to get your ass up today,
go out and look for a job.
The word today is job.
J-O-B.
- You hear me?
Yeah.
You go look for a job today.
I'm not kidding.
Open all the windows.
Damn, it stinks in here.
Where mine at?
Oh, I didn't say I was cooking nothing for you.
This is for me.
Have some cereal.
We ain't got no milk.
Use water.
It won't hurt.
Oh, man.
- Huh?
- Nothing.
Break yourself, fool.
Look what you did to my curtain.
Better watch who window you climbing in
before you get blasted on.
With what?
You ain't got nothing, man.
With this.
- Where you get that from?
- Your mama.
- Fuck you.
Come on outside, man, stop playing.
Heh, heh, heh.
Gotta get dressed.
Hurry up.
- Don't tell me to hurry up.
Damn.
What's up, Big Worm?
How much you got left?
- Man, I got a lot.
- You still ain't sold that weed, Smokey?
Man, I'm trying to, Worm.
Niggers are broke these days.
I don't think you applying yourself,
Smokey.
Huh?
- You smoking my shit?
- Hell, no. Fuck with your shit? Hell, no.
- Why would I do some shit like that?
I don't wanna have to fuck you up,
Smokey.
Playing with my money
is like playing with my emotions.
Worm.
Hey, you the last brother money
I'd mess with.
I'll steal from my mama
before I mess with your shit.
And you know this, man.
We'll see.
Old Florida Evans-looking motherfucker.
- What's up, man?
- What's up?
Why you ain't at work?
I got fired yesterday.
For real?
I thought you had the day off yesterday.
I did.
I went in there to pick up my check.
Came home.
Supervisor called me about 4:00.
Talking about they got me on video tape
stealing boxes.
What the fuck you doing
stealing boxes for?
What, you trying to build a clubhouse?
- Man, I know you ain't go out like that.
- Hell, no.
They ain't got me on tape.
She said they did.
Fired me on the spot.
Talking about pressing charges.
Goddamn, you got to be a stupid
motherfucker to get fired on your day off.
- Pops talking about kicking you out again?
- Yup.
Oh, goddamn.
Man, look.
Hi, you guys.
Heey.
Ooh.
Man, man, man.
Her mama got ass too.
Just give me three and a half minutes,
maybe even four...
...she'll be wanting to marry a nigger.
- Who, her mama?
- Yeah.
Older the berry, the sweeter the juice.
It's the blacker the berry,
the sweeter the juice.
Yeah, well, yeah.
She blacker than a motherfucker too.
I ain't fucking with you.
Watch out.
She wanted to give me the ass
one time, I had to go to work and shit.
I wonder where she going.
She probably going to that new health club
down on 108th.
- Oh, so they opened that already?
-Yep.
I heard they hiring too.
You need to go down there and see
what's up, with your out-of-work ass.
Hey, hold up.
My mom's in there.
She about to go to work though.
Hey.
I know you don't smoke weed.
I know this.
But I'm gonna get you high today.
Because it's Friday.
You ain't got no job.
And you ain't got shit to do.
Anyway, what you doing up so early?
Oh, man, I tried to come and catch you
before you went to work...
...let you know
what happened to Red's ass.
What's up?
Man, you know that nigger Deebo
done had his bike for three weeks, right?
- Right.
- Man....
I got so much money,
I got another nigger just to count it for me.
I won.
Give me my money.
- You what?
- I lost.
Roll the dice.
Deebo.
Hold my money.
- Watch him.
Can I talk to you for a second?
Oh, shit.
Pop's tripping, man.
He want me to ask for my bike back.
You know I wouldn't trip.
- What bike?
- The beach cruiser.
The one I let you use a couple of weeks ago.
The one I been asking you about.
Oh.
That bike.
I didn't know you wanted it back, homey.
It's right here.
Follow me, homey.
It's just like it's both ours.
- We just keep it down at my house.
- Cool.
Oh, shit!
- Oh.
That's my bike, punk!
Goddamn.
You got knocked the fuck out.
- You want some of this too, old man, huh?
- No.
Get off your ass and get in this car.
Boy, I don't know why you come down here
messing with these people.
Hurry up.
Man, they both got in the car
and boned out.
- You lying.
- I swear to God.
- We was rolling.
- Damn.
Craig, tell that little girl
to stop playing on my phone.
- What little girl?
- Joi. She keeps calling, hanging up.
And I know it's her because I star-69'd her.
She hung up again.
I don't like her disrespecting my house.
- Now, you tell her I said to stop it, all right?
- Okay.
Hi, Mrs. Jones.
Hi, Smokey!
Damn.
What time your mama leaving?
In a little while.
Why?
Because I wanna smoke this joint.
Let's go to my house real quick.
Can't do shit over here.
- Damn, Lil Chris got you too?
- Hell, yeah.
Got me too, little bitch-ass nigger.
If I catch him,
I'm gonna beat him like I was his dad.
Excuse me?
What?
Could y'all stay off my grass, please?
Thank you.
Stanley be acting like a old bitch.
I know.
Nothing but dirt any damn way.
Remember this?
- Hey, man.
Shut up.
Damn.
Mama.
Damn, Smoke. What you doing
knocking like you the damn police?
I'm in here on the phone.
I left my key.
Always talking shit.
Just can't open the goddamn door.
Stop slamming my goddamn door.
- Sorry, Joann.
Come in here.
You don't wanna hear that shit.
- Ha, ha, ha. Yes, I did.
- Get your ass up and cook...
...or clean up or do something.
Always talking shit.
Damn.
All you do is smoke weed.
That's all right.
Don't worry about what fuck
I be doing.
What I'm tripping on...
...is how you gonna sell bud...
...and you smoking it?
I don't know.
- That's my only problem.
- Big Worm gonna end up fucking you up.
Big Worm ain't gonna do
a goddamn thing, man.
All right.
Look, he need me.
Red told me he smoked a fool
for 50 bucks.
I don't give a fuck.
Smokey, I need you to go to the store
and get me some cigarettes.
Give me the money.
Wait, wait, wait. Wait a minute.
What's this?
This ain't enough.
Make it enough.
Damn.
Oh, yeah.
Smokey.
Smokey. Smokey.
Smokey, wait.
Hey, let me wash your car for $2.
Hell, no, you'll smoke it up.
No, man.
Smoke, no. I don't smoke no more.
- Get off me.
- Buy me a 40 ounce for my birthday.
Today your birthday?
What's today?
- Man, come on.
- All right.
- Oh, I'm shot.
Get your ass off me.
I need some papers...
...and some humps.
Hey.
Get these for me.
I ain't got no money. Not enough.
- You owe me two dollars.
Add these.
Aah! Oh, my God. Oh, my God.
I'm hurt.
Yah! Oh, I fall.
I'm suing y'all.
I'm hurt.
Oh, my neck.
My back.
My neck and my back. Oh.
I want 150,000.
We can settle out of court now
for 20 bucks.
Man, get your punk ass up.
It ain't even wet over here. Damn.
Look here, give me 10 dollars,
and I won't say nothing.
- Get out. Get out.
- 2.50 and a jawbreaker?
- Dollar and some envelopes.
What you doing?
You know how much money you can get
for a slip and fall?
- You need to stay off that crack.
- Get out.
You wrong, brother.
You wrong.
- You wrong. He wrong.
Get out.
Brother, stay black.
He was... I don't like that.
Hell, no.
Watch out.
Hey, thanks, Smoke.
Thanks, my ass.
You better come by my house, wash my car.
- Be there.
- I'm serious.
All right.
Goddamn.
- Goddamn.
Stop your shit.
Stop the mother...
Dizam.
Fuck.
Watch my car,
make sure nobody mess with it.
Damn.
Mrs. Parker finer than a motherfucker.
I'd knock the dust off that pussy.
Damn.
Hi, Mrs. Parker.
Hi, boys.
When you going to let me fuck,
Mrs. Parker?
What'd you say, honey?
Huh?
Nothing.
Mrs. Parker just don't know.
Needs some young meat.
Mr. Parker ain't hitting that right, man.
She know what she's doing
with them little ass shorts on.
She know we be looking.
Craig, I'm on my way to work.
Make sure if you leave,
you lock up the house.
Answer the phone,
the cable people are supposed to call.
All right.
Look at her.
She ought to be ashamed of herself
coming out looking like that.
Hey, girl.
Hey, how you doing?
Fine.
I'm on my way to work.
Call me when you get home.
Okay.
Hey, go in the house
and get me something to roll this up with.
All right.
Hey, and bring a radio too.
Hello?
Holy shit.
It's hot as hell out here.
You a hype.
- What?
- You a hype.
Man, ain't nothing wrong
with smoking weed.
Weed is from the earth.
God put this here for me and you.
Take advantage, man.
Take advantage.
Hey, fuck, man.
Put that out, man.
Here come the pastor.
For what?
He probably smoke bud too.
How you doing, Brother Craig?
- How you doing?
- I'm all right.
Well, I see.
By any chance is Sister Jones in?
Nope.
Neither is Brother Jones, they both at work.
Where your ass need to be, nigger.
Excuse me, brother.
What we call drugs
at 74th Street Baptist Church...
...we call a sinny-sin-sin
Well, around here
Between Normandie and Western
We call this here
A little twenty-twen-twen'
- Wow
- Nigger
Give me a little for my cataracts?
- You didn't put in on this, man.
- Better to give than to receive, brother.
Look, look, look.
She bending over.
Good Lord, have mercy.
The Lord is my shepherd,
he know what I want. Excuse me.
Mrs. Parker.
Mrs. Parker. Can I talk...
I told you, the weed be letting you know
evil lurks.
Look, Hector almost hit his nasty ass.
What's up, Smokey?
Fuck you.
Why you don't like Hector?
I was telling you I was smoking weed
with that fool one day.
So you decided to smoke
with the big boys, huh, Smokey?
You ain't showing me nothing new, ese.
Shut up and take a hit.
Smoke Dog, baby.
Remember that shit.
Been smoking since I was 2.
Hey, hey, hey.
Take it easy, homes.
I know what I'm doing, man.
Shut the fuck up.
Homestead, yo, take it easy, ese.
What's this?
It's angel dust, homes.
So I hit it real hard, right?
As soon as he said that...
...I started feeling funny as hell.
Next thing I knew, I was running
down the street in my damn drawers.
Hey, man.
Get off me.
Get off me, man.
Goddamn.
Motherfuckers.
Get off me.
I'm in Deebo's pigeon coop
sweating like a slave.
And the only person who could get me out
was my mom.
And, man,
I ain't been right ever since then.
That's why I been like, "Fuck Hector."
Yeah, I remember that.
Peep.
Damn.
Listen.
Man, that's Lil Chris.
Let's go get his ass.
Quit playing.
Don't let me catch you, boy.
Stop. Stop, man.
Quit playing.
I'm gonna knock them over next week.
Man, y'all some busters.
Y'all can't see me, punks.
Nigger, you slow.
- Run like a girl.
- Fuck you.
Oh, shit.
Here come Deebo.
- Give me your stuff.
- Oh, shit.
Known for jacking a nigger.
That's all he do. Damn.
- What's up, Smoke?
- Nothing.
What you got on my drink?
Nothing.
Don't lie.
Got nothing, man.
What you got, Craig?
I'm broke as a joke.
Y'all some high rollers and y'all broke.
What's up, Stanley?
Well, fuck you then, punk.
Telling Craig,
Stanley's been acting funny lately.
Stanley left his window open, man.
Come on, Smoke, let's go in.
I'm on probation, I can't be....
Stop being a bitch and come on.
Craig, if somebody comes, whistle.
I ain't trying to get involved.
If you don't get involved,
I'm gonna knock your ass out too.
Make a choice.
Man, hurry up.
You a bitch!
Bitch!
For some reason, I don't think
Smokey wanted to go in there...
...but peer pressure's a motherfucker.
Come on, nigger.
Damn.
Always caught in the middle of something.
Dump your ass over the window.
Hurry up, shit.
Hurry up.
- Pick it up.
Hey, hey.
Oh, shit.
It's on now.
- Damn.
Watch my foot.
Hurry up.
Come on, man. Bring your ass out.
Come on.
Get off my ass!
Shit.
Hurry up.
Get off my ass.
I ain't with that funny shit.
Hello.
Oh, man.
Come on.
Goddamn.
Just wait till I get my hands on you.
Baby, baby, we was just praying.
We was just praying.
I'll kill him.
- Aah!
- We was just praying.
I'll get you.
Goddamn devil.
He wasn't even that good, baby.
I'll kill you.
Yeah, I know.
Damn.
Come on.
Get your feet down.
Come on, man.
Move it.
- What took y'all so long?
- This fool's scared. He didn't even...
Look, fellas.
I asked you nicely.
Now I'm getting very irritated.
For the last time, would you please stay off
my frigging grass, please.
All right, man. Sorry.
Thank you.
Scary ass didn't wanna touch nothing.
- Was in there whole time arguing.
- So y'all didn't get nothing?
Hell, yeah.
We got about 200 dollars, huh, Deebo?
I got about 200 dollars.
Uh....
One day somebody gonna kick his ass.
Man, I've been getting high all week.
Take a puff.
- Take a hit.
- You watch out.
Craig.
Ain't like you got shit to do tomorrow.
You don't have to go to work.
Now, take a hit.
I drink.
Craig, it'll stimulate your mind.
You ain't got shit to do.
All right.
Put it in your mouth.
Shut up.
That's the shit, ain't it?
That's the shit.
Wet the motherfucker all up.
It's my shit.
I can do whatever I wanna do.
Stop hitting it so hard.
You fucking up the rotation.
Puff, puff, give.
Fucking up the rotation.
You could get killed with somebody else.
That's some serious shit.
You're lucky you're my boy.
Oh, shit.
Take your time.
Gotta crawl before you walk.
You high yet?
Craig, you fucked up.
You fucked up.
You said this was indo.
Smell like outdo.
Hey, wait a minute, man.
I ain't gonna be supplying you
you gonna be talking about my shit.
Oh, shit.
Here come Felisha.
Old begging ass.
I know.
What's up, Craig?
- What's up, Smokey?
- Nothing.
What y'all smoking on?
Nothing.
What you want?
Oh.
I need to borrow your car quick.
What kind of shit is that?
Most people wanna borrow sugar
or even ketchup.
You wanna borrow my car?
Hell, no.
- Get the hell on.
- Let me borrow a joint.
You need to borrow a job,
with your broke ass.
Always trying to smoke up
somebody's shit.
Get the hell on, Felisha.
I'll remember that.
Remember it. Write it down.
Take a picture. I don't give a fuck.
Craig?
Bye, Felisha.
Y'all stingy.
Goddamn pest.
Oh, man.
This bud is kicking in.
Don't start tripping, Craig.
Smoke.
I ain't tripping.
Craig.
Craig. Craig.
Hold up.
I can hear my heart beat.
Man, that what it's supposed to do.
No, my shit beating too fast.
It's the chronic.
Don't even worry about it.
Listen.
You don't hear it?
Hell, no.
I knew I shouldn't have given him
no chronic.
You hear my phone ring?
Man, hell, no.
Man, sit down.
I'm on house arrest.
I'm not even supposed to be over here.
Get a nigger locked up.
Man, come on.
Come in.
I'm thirsty.
- You be tripping, man. Come on.
- Shut up.
Sit your skinny ass down.
You want some Kool-Aid?
Man, you know I want some Kool-Aid.
You smoking my weed too?
I'm gonna kill you and Smokey.
You're playing with my emotions.
Damn.
What?
I ain't got no sugar.
You ain't got no sugar?
Damn.
Y'all ain't never got two things
that match.
Either y'all got Kool-Aid, no sugar...
...peanut butter, no jelly...
...ham, no burger.
Damn.
You're a funny looking motherfucker.
Man, hold up.
I don't do that gay shit, now.
You want me
to go get the sugar or what?
Yes.
Oh, shit.
It's the motherfucking cops.
They know I'm over here.
Shit.
Watch out.
Is it the cops?
Hey, what's up?
Come on in.
Is Dana here?
- Uh....
No. No.
She ain't came home from school.
- You ain't seen her?
- Debbie.
What?
Come here.
Sit down.
Hi, Smokey.
- You had a friend wanna hook up with me.
- I do.
- First, how she look?
- She's nice.
She got a big booty?
Smokey, I'm not trying to look
at that girl's booty, all right?
You know you done
looked at her booty before.
Just call her, all right?
- She at home?
- She should be.
Cheap ass phone.
Come over here and sit down.
Right here.
You're way over there.
Hey, uh, this is Smokey.
Debbie's homeboy.
She said you wanted to hook up.
Craig.
What's up?
- Are you high?
- Huh?
- No, why you say that?
Because you look
like you've been smoking.
For real?
No, I'm cool.
Do I still look high?
Now, describe yourself.
I'm about 5'2",
light-skinned, long hair.
I'm thick.
People say I look like Janet Jackson.
For real?
No shit?
Janet Jackson?
Oh, boy.
You know,
your sister came by here today, begging.
- Who, Felisha?
- Yes.
She is a trip, I know.
Why don't you come over.
Come to my homey's house.
All right.
He live on Debbie's street?
Yeah.
You know Dana, right?
The other day I had to stop Deebo
from beating her ass.
What?
Yes. When he gets high and drunk
he starts tripping.
One time he grabbed me.
- No.
- Yes, grabbed me like this.
For real?
I mean, was it like this or was it like this?
Ooh, um...
I think it was the first one.
- It was the first? You sure?
- Mm-hm.
What the fuck?
Oh, man, I'm tripping.
What's wrong?
Am I tripping?
I, uh...
I got to go in here.
In the back room real quick.
- All right. All right.
Bye.
I ain't getting high no more.
Ain't getting high no more.
Shit.
- So, what's up? Did you guys hook up?
- It's cool.
- All right, well, I'm about to go home.
You know,
my homey wanna hook up with you.
- Who?
- Craig.
Craig already has a woman.
But he don't like her.
I'll see you later.
Why you tell her I wanna hook up?
She don't be believing me.
I'm high.
Hey.
What's with you and that chickenhead?
Oh.
Man.
She said she looked like Janet Jackson.
- You lucky.
- And you know this, man.
Oh, man.
- Hey, Dad.
- Oh.
What happened to you?
I got bit in the ass today, son.
By a stinking-ass filthy dog.
You should have seen it.
Biggest dog I've ever seen in my life.
I said, "Doggy,
please don't bite me, dog."
And I turned around to jump over the fence,
the dog grabbed my ass.
I told you.
- I told you.
- You didn't tell me shit.
Y'all get on the front porch
with all that damn noise.
Was it like, "grawr"?
- How your ass feel Mr. Jones?
- Get out of my house.
- Don't slam that door.
- All right, man.
Hey. You kids,
quit slamming my goddamn door.
Damn.
Oh, shit.
What you gonna do?
Hey, hey, hey.
- What you want?
- What you got?
Boy, what the fuck you want?
Give me some chili Fritos.
Come here.
What's up, Big Perm?
I mean, Big Worm.
- You sell that bud?
- I sold some of it.
Give me the rest. Somebody want
a couple of 20s around the corner.
No, I'm just bullshitting.
I sold that shit.
- Then count out my money.
- Hurry up.
Don't you see we handling
grown folks business?
Damn.
Now, shut the hell up.
20.
40, 60, 80.
A hundred, 120, 140.
Wait, man. That's 100 dollars.
Stop playing with me, Smokey.
You know what happened?
You're gonna laugh you're ass off.
You know Craig?
- Craig got fired yesterday.
- What the fuck that gotta do with me?
Let me explain.
We was talking
over all our problems, right?
And you know how we do it.
We started getting high.
Nigga, we go fucked up.
Look, nigga, I'm gonna be here
at 10:00 on the dot.
Not 10:03, not 10:36.
If you ain't got my money or my bud,
I'm killing you and him.
- You're gonna kill me?
- Get the fuck out of my face.
Back, back.
Can I have my chili Fritos?
You can't have shit.
I'm closed, fat boy.
Then give me my money back.
- It's my money.
Mama.
I hate him.
- What'd he say?
- Huh?
What'd he say?
Oh, he just said for us to pay him
by 10:00.
What you mean "us"?
Man, that fool ain't gonna do nothing.
Man, I know you didn't...
- Worm!
- What you doing?
- Craig.
- Worm!
Damn.
What's up?
- What did you tell him?
- I just told him we was smoking.
And we was just chilling.
Man, you were smoking.
I smoked half a little piece of joint
with you.
- That fool ain't gonna do nothing.
- What'd he say?
What'd he say?
If we don't pay him by 10:00,
he gonna bust a cap in both our ass.
Nigga, we need to pay, he crazy.
Let's stick together.
I can't believe you got me in the mix
with this fool.
I didn't put that joint to your lip,
make you smoke.
Might as well.
"Come on, Craig, man."
"Stimulate you mind, man."
"It's Friday."
"We'll get you high."
Why you bringing up old shit?
Craig.
I left my purse in your house.
Can I go in and get it?
- Yeah, come on.
- All right.
Fool?!
- Where Craig at?
- Fool?
Oh, he's in the house.
Hell, no.
Who is that bitch?
Yeah, who's that bitch?
Who you talking to?
Nigga, I'm talking to you.
Now, who is she?
That's just Debbie from down the street.
So?
What the hell's she doing in there?
She was just... Just go in the house.
- What you looking at?
- Get your ass in the house.
Hurry up.
Look, I'm gonna straighten this girl out.
I'll be right back.
All right, man. I'm gonna go
to the crib, man. My stomach hurt.
Hey.
- Come back.
- All right.
Watch this.
Whoo!
Mama.
Shit.
What the hell you want, boy?
Damn.
Mr. Jones,
can I use your bathroom, please?
What you gonna do?
Number one or number two?
- Number two.
- Shit.
You ain't gonna drop
no stinky loads here.
Anybody drop stinky loads, it's me.
Mr. Jones.
Mama.
Shit.
Smokey.
Smokey, what the hell you doing
back here?
Nothing, man. I'm fixing something.
Just stay over there.
- I thought you wanted me to wash your car.
- Hey, man. Wash it later. Stay over there.
I'm not the smartest man in the world...
...but from here
it looks like you taking a shit.
Ezal, get the hell out of my backyard.
You been eating corn, huh?
Man, get the hell out of my backyard,
man.
All right, nigga, look. When you're done,
I'll clean all that shit up for you for $2.
Hey, Ezal.
- What?
- You better not tell nobody, man.
I'm not, man.
- Keep it on down low.
- I'm not like that. I'm gonna keep it down.
Hey, Smokey's back here taking a shit!
Ezal!
Well, I ain't gonna tell nobody else.
You need to control
that little funky ass temper.
I know.
I be forgetting, baby.
You gotta be reminding me.
I'm sorry.
My mama know that's you calling
and hanging up.
Why?
That ain't me calling
and hanging up, baby.
You know I love your mama.
Hey, you got some money?
What?
Some huh?
Nigga, how much you need?
About 200 dollars.
Well, I guess so.
What you gonna give me?
Craig.
Craig. Craig.
Can I talk to you for a minute?
What?
Can I use y'all's VCR right quick?
Wanna dub a tape.
- Hell, no.
- It's The Mack.
Wait a minute.
Who the fuck is that bitch?
Fuck you, motherfucker.
You think you're slick,
gonna ask me for some money.
Go ask that bitch for some money.
Damn.
What's wrong with your ho?
We had the money, right here,
my motherfucker.
We ain't have shit.
So, what we gonna do?
That fool's just playing, man.
I ain't sweating it.
That's your problem.
Ain't nobody playing but you.
You walk up and down this street
all day playing.
He ain't playing.
You think he playing about his money?
You done dragged me into this.
He know where my mama stay,
know where your mama stay.
You say he had a gun
when you've seen him, right?
- Yeah.
- Name one person in the hood...
...that play like that.
I know, huh?
Look, man...
...I'm sorry I got you in this shit.
I'm gonna tell him
you ain't got nothing to do with it.
I smoked up his weed.
I'm gonna face the consequences.
If I get dealt with, I get dealt with.
Hey, Craig, have you seen my shoe...?
What's that for?
Protection.
Protection?
Protection from who?
Me and Smokey...
I got to walk Smokey down to his house.
Oh, man.
I never would've moved in...
...if we had known you need a gun
to walk down the damn street.
You know how it is around here.
Oh, no, son.
That's not the way it is.
You kids today ain't nothing but punks.
Sissified.
So quick to pick up a gun.
You scared to take an ass whipping.
This what makes you a man.
When I was growing up,
this was all the protection we needed.
You win some, you lose some.
But you live,
you live to fight another day.
You think you're a man
with that gun in your hand, don't you?
I'm a man without it.
Put the gun down.
Come on, put up your dukes.
Now you're a man.
Your uncle picked up a gun too.
He had to find out the hard way.
22 years old.
You got a choice.
These are all you need.
All right?
What's up, man?
- What's up, Red?
- Get your ass up.
- Oh.
Oh, they was clowning you
at work today, man.
- So what?
- I saw the tape.
We kept rewinding it.
It kind of looked like your head,
but you can't tell from the back.
- How your eye?
- Oh, it's cool.
Damn!
Put your glasses back on.
What's up, Craig?
What's up, Red?
Hey, Smokey.
Sell me a dub.
I ain't selling you nada.
Oh, come on, homes.
Let's let bygones be bygones.
Race the fuck off
before Craig's father come out here.
You need to go on and do that.
Hey, I ain't selling him shit.
Better get your ass off your shoulders.
You ain't gonna get me shot up.
You better make that money.
- Hurry up.
- Hey, ese.
Man, this nigger...
...got us in some shit.
That shit was fucked up.
- It's all right. You have nice legs.
Fuck you.
Shit, here comes Deebo.
Who?
- Deebo.
I'm gonna just tuck mine in.
What's up, y'all?
What's up, Red?
Thanks for the bike.
Where you got my 40, homey?
I thought you had 200 dollars.
I do.
But I wanna spend Red's money.
I'm broke.
Give it up, Red.
Come on, Deebo, stall him out.
Where you got on my 40, homey?
I don't have nothing.
Yeah, you got something.
- Why are you tripping, Deebo?
- Shut up or I knock your ass.
Oh, man, that's messed up.
Why don't you give him back his chain?
What chain?
Yeah, what chain?
Hey, why you didn't help me?
Man, I'm high.
Man, that's fucked up, man.
If it was y'all, I would've helped y'all.
What about the time he tried to choke me
in Smoke's backyard?
Yeah.
That was different.
Men, let's jump him.
Sit your ass down.
Man, I got mind control over Deebo.
He be, like, "Shut the fuck up."
I be quiet.
But when he leave...
...I be talking again.
Man, my grandmama
gave me that chain.
He tripping hard.
Only on people he know.
He don't be pulling that shit
on them fools around the corner.
Man, fuck that.
He gonna cry in the car.
Here come Dana.
- And her punk ass boyfriend.
Bye, baby.
What are you doing with that
on your head?
Don't even ask.
All right, don't get homeboy fucked up.
Debbie came by looking for you.
For real?
What she say?
She just said to tell you she came by.
All right.
Hey, Dana.
- When we gonna hook up?
- Boy, please.
Elvira. Elvira!
That's okay!
She'll be back.
Another Quaalude,
she'll love me in the morning.
- Ain't that right, friend?
- Get off me.
- Oh! He's crazy! He's crazy!
- Oh, shit.
He's crazy!
- He's going off.
Goddamn preacher.
Craig.
Craig, Daddy wants you.
Look.
- What Daddy want?
- I don't know. Go see.
Craig.
- Tell me if anything happens.
- Go see.
Hey, what's up with me and you?
I in there was on the phone with Debbie,
and what's up with Rita?
- Rita who?
- Rita that's gonna be here at 7:30.
Girl, that's my friend.
Dana, wait up.
Anything else happen?
No.
Look at Ezal.
Scandalous.
Damn.
Is Dana in there?
Yeah.
Just go on and knock.
- What's your name?
China. Excuse me.
- Stop.
Don't come here with that attitude.
What's up?
- Nothing. Just got off that bus.
- Did you remember to pick up the hair?
- Yeah.
Daddy wants you again.
Damn.
- What he want?
Go see.
Outrun the dog.
Run.
Go for the tree, Mr. Postman. Go.
Huh?
Get me glass of water.
It's your ass, Mr. Postman.
I look like the Kunta Kinte
around this mother?
Go, go, go.
Go.
- Took long enough.
- I know.
All right, here's what we're gonna do.
I'm gonna run here and get you the gun.
Then I'm gonna go home to chill.
You wait for them niggers.
And later on, you call me
and let me know what happened, all right?
You're making me nervous, okay?
Hey, I'm tripping. I ain't scared of shit.
I'm doing good.
Stop.
- Damn.
- All right.
Damn.
Whose car is that?
I don't know.
I don't know who car that is.
Hey, what time is it?
Seven forty-five.
Oh.
Nigger, that's Janet Jackson.
- Who?
- Janet Jackson.
- The girl Debbie hooked me up with.
- Oh.
Hey, hold up.
I'll be right back.
Hey, see if she got a friend.
- All right.
Ooh.
What's up?
Not a damn thing.
So we gonna kick it or what?
We can kick it, but I forgot
I have to go pick up my mom from work.
Hey, you know how that is.
- That's all right. I'll take you to get her.
- No.
She don't like people with me
when I go get her.
Who's that girl Smokey's talking to?
Some girl he hooked up with.
She's a big one.
Humongous.
Go and get something to eat.
I know you hungry.
Oh, Lord, let me go inside and see
what's going on with this crazy man.
- I'm right behind you.
- Okay.
- Uh-uh because I ate twice before I came.
- Goddamn!
Craig, where the iron?
Right there.
Hey, Dana?
- What?
- Loan me 200 dollars.
Me and Smokey got into it
with Big Worm today.
We owe him 200 dollars.
He said if we don't pay him,
he gonna kill us.
Are you gonna loan me the money?
Not.
- You gonna call me?
- I'm gonna call you.
But if you come by,
I won't call you, okay?
Don't ever, ever...
...ever, ever, ever...
...come by here.
Okay?
- Okay.
- All right.
Bye, Smokey.
Debbie girl, damn.
Craig.
Telephone.
- Who is it?
- That girl.
- Tell her I'll call her back.
- Okay.
Hey, Mama.
What?
Loan me 200 dollars.
Craig, I wouldn't feel comfortable
lending you 200 dollars without a job.
If I was working,
I wouldn't need 200 dollars.
Exactly.
Y'all ain't never got no money.
I hate living around
a bunch of broke-ass people.
Shit.
Come here.
What?
Why you hook me up
with that fat-ass baldhead girl?
- Who, Rita?
- Yeah.
Rita is not fat, she's just big-boned.
Shit.
That girl wider than all outside.
- Talking about she look like Janet Jackson.
- Ooh. She didn't go there?
Bitch got out of the car
looking more like Freddie Jackson.
- Don't laugh.
It ain't funny.
I'm sorry.
I'm not trying to laugh. I just thought
you two would like each other.
You knew she was bald head.
You knew she had no damn hair.
Don't laugh.
It ain't funny.
Aw.
I'm sorry.
What Deebo doing over here?
Oh, he's in there asleep with Felisha.
- Felisha fucking Deebo too?
- Could you mind your own business.
Where your mama at?
My mama is in Vegas with her boyfriend.
So y'all just parlaying up in here, huh?
- Oh, shit.
Party over here.
What?
Bye-bye.
Oh, you tripping.
I'm out of here anyway.
Peace out.
Nasty motherfucker.
Damn.
- Smokey? What are you doing in here?
- What the hell are you doing here?
- I see the window open so I said fuck it.
- Get the hell out of here.
- All right, man. Look, here, loan me $2.
- Man, get the fuck out.
Damn.
Fucking bitch.
I'm clowning.
Janet Jackson ass get just a little fat.
Man, forget that.
I almost had the money.
- What?
- That money we stole from Stanley house?
- Me and Deebo?
- Yeah.
Deebo was over at Felisha house
and Debbie house asleep.
Man, I snuck through the back window
to get the money.
Just when I was gonna get the money,
Ezal come running and woke him up.
- Damn.
- I tried to beat his ass, but he ran.
Oh, you ain't catching no crackhead.
Let's just go back over there.
He probably still asleep.
- For real?
- Yeah, you breaking in though.
- You with me?
- I got you.
- Let's go.
- All right.
Damn.
Oh, well...
...forget that plan.
What time is it?
08:50.
I'm just gonna go in the house
and chill, man.
Oh. Now you're scared.
You wanna go in and lay down?
Man, hell, no.
Nobody gonna run me up in my house
like no bitch.
This my hood.
Fuck Worm.
Boo.
Punk.
Man, y'all busters can't catch me.
Hold him.
All right, man.
Mama!
We finally got him.
We just did it.
We got that little motherfucker.
Calm down.
What?
Who car is that coming up creeping?
Drive-by.
Get off my ass.
Hey, let's go in the house.
Slipping.
I wish you weren't slipping today.
Shit.
Who is that?
Big Worm.
Hey, um...
...somebody...
...page Smokey?
Don't play dumb, nigger.
You know who this is. You got my money?
Man, you don't have to holler, man.
I ain't got it yet but I'm gonna get it...
What happened?
Man, he just hung up.
I think we better stay in the house.
Damn.
See anything?
Man, I can't see shit.
Stanley trees all in the way.
- I'm gonna try again.
- Hey, hey, hey.
Now Dana told me
about that Big Snake situation.
- Big Worm.
- Big Worm, Big Hole, Big...
I don't give a damn.
Get your ass out of this house, boy.
You always got some shit going.
And you, you keep your ass here.
Big Snake. Big Worm.
What kind of name is that?
I bet y'all drinking that wine.
Smoking them tweeds and everything.
Wearing them clothes all half-off your ass,
what the hell is going on today?
- Weed.
Your punk-ass dad,
he always talking shit.
- Just wait, wait. Well, hold up.
- Tell him to comb his goddamn hair.
Like a bunch of spiders
is having a meeting on his head.
- I'm about sick of you. Naw.
- I'm sick of you.
I'll walk you, man, you punk ass.
You see him?
Man, ain't nobody even out here.
I don't even know why I'm tripping.
Nobody wanna mess
with the Smoke Dog.
Hey, who's that?
Oh, shit.
Quick, quick, quick.
You don't know who you messing with,
Smoke Dog, nigger.
Damn.
Come on, get out of here.
Hurry up, hurry up, hurry up.
Goddamn, goddamn.
Hey, hey, hey.
- Look and see if they're gone.
- Hell, no. You look.
Hey, we both look.
- On the count of three.
- All right.
- One, two, three.
- Two, three.
- Craig, I thought you said on three.
- Okay. All right.
- You ain't bullshitting?
- Come on.
- One, two, three.
- All right, one, two, three.
- What the fuck you...?
- You see them?
- Yeah, they coming, man.
- Oh, shit.
I ain't going ever smoke weed again.
- Craig, I love you, man.
- Shut up.
Man, don't tou...
Let me go.
Mama.
Shut up, man.
Her fat ass couldn't do nothing.
I want my mama.
Man. Man.
I swear to you. Yeah, I shot one.
I know I shot one of them.
Hey, hey.
- Look again.
Fuck you.
Stanley.
What's going on?
I don't know.
It sounded like machine guns.
Oh, Lord.
- Mama, where Craig at?
- I don't know.
There's Joann.
Go ask her if she's seen them.
It sounded like a bomb.
- Joann, you seen Craig and Smokey?
- I thought they were over there.
Deebo.
You seen Craig and Smokey around here?
Earlier.
Damn.
- What she say?
- She ain't seen them.
Deebo ain't seen them neither.
You have to tell us
before you leave the house.
Look at your face.
- It will be okay. Believe me.
- No, look at your face.
Who do you think you are?
- What you talking about?
- You know what I'm talking about.
You hit my sister
like she was a fucking man.
She had no business
going through my pants.
My sister don't need to steal nothing
from your broke ass, all right?
- Better take your ass home.
- I'm not scared of you.
All these niggers around here
might be scared of you.
But I'm not.
- You take your ass home.
- No, fuck you.
You're lucky I'm not a man.
Otherwise, I'd kick your ass myself.
Shut up!
Deebo, man.
You tripping.
What you say, little nigger?
Man, that's a female.
Shut your little punk ass up, nigger,
before I drop you like I did this bitch.
Man, I ain't even trying to fight you,
Deebo.
Ezal.
I know you don't wanna fight me
because you're nothing but a bitch too.
What you gonna do with that
besides make me mad?
Put the gun down, son.
Huh?
Yeah.
Put that gun down, son...
...and get knocked out
like your father used to.
This was all the protection we needed.
You win some, you lose some.
But you live.
You live to fight another day.
You think you're a man
with that gun in your hand.
I'm a man without it.
Yeah.
Put that gun down, son...
...and get knocked out
like your father used to.
Give me the gun, son.
Craig.
Give me the gun.
Give me the gun, son.
That's all you got?
Get him.
Damn.
Drop him, Craig. Drop him, Craig.
Drop him, Craig.
Deebo.
Damn.
Hurry, quick.
- Craig. Oh, shit.
There you go, Craig.
There you go.
Get up, Craig. Get up, Craig.
- Yeah.
- Come on, nigger.
Yeah.
- Yeah.
- Come on, Craig.
Oh, shit, goddamn.
Goddamn.
No.
- No. No, come on, baby. Let him be a man.
- Go to sleep. Go to sleep.
Do something.
- Yeah.
- Do something.
- Shoot him.
Stop it.
- See, he's not fighting fair.
Come on, man, kill him.
I been down before.
I taught him better than this.
Craig, get up.
- Get up, Craig. Come on, Craig.
- Come on, Craig.
I told y'all.
You all want some?
Beat him down, beat you down.
Who else wants some?
Who else wants some of Deebo?
- Who else?
Craig, get up.
Get up, Craig.
Come on, Craig.
Fair enough, Craig. Fair enough.
There you go.
All right, Craig.
Hey, punk.
Yes, Mr. Big Shot.
Fucking... Yeah.
Crawl, punk.
Crawl, you little bitch.
- Whoop him, Craig. Whoop his ass.
- There, buddy.
Ooh.
That's what I'm talking about.
That's my dog.
- Take that.
Ain't that right, Ma?
That's my dog.
Mr. Parker.
- That's my dog.
- Cutie pie.
If anybody gotta say anything,
you let me know.
That's my dog.
That's what I'm talking about.
Are you okay?
- Craig.
- No, no, cupcakes. Leave him alone.
Now, let him be a man.
I taught him good, didn't I?
Now who's the punk?
- He think he a mack.
- Macaroni.
You got knocked the fuck out, man.
Give me my goddamn money.
Payback's a motherfucker,
ain't it, nigger?
China, come on.
No, Ma.
Stop, you're embarrassing me.
My grandmama gave me this chain.
Deebo!
Man, you should've been
bobbing and weaving. Look at you.
Get up!
Since you ain't getting up,
I'll take these shoes.
Bigfoot motherfucker,
you can have your knife.
Because I steal, I don't kill.
Craig, yeah.
How's your back feeling?
It be cool.
Bleeding and shit.
What time you waking up
in the morning?
8:30, why?
I was just wondering that maybe
if you were feeling better, um...
...that you could come over.
I'm feeling better already.
I'm gonna call you tomorrow.
All right.
8:30, right?
Yes.
Hey, 7:30.
That's right.
Craig, come here.
- Craig.
- Huh?
Shut the door and have a seat.
Can I leave the door open?
Shut the door.
Now you see, son. You gotta let us know
when you leave the house.
What if you got killed tonight?
We'd have to bury you.
You know how much a funeral costs
these days?
No.
About 4 or $5000.
I ain't got no 4 or $5000
to plant you in the ground.
- You understand?
- Yeah.
You keep your ass around this house.
Your supervisor called about your job.
She wants you to call tomorrow.
- For real?
- Mm-hm.
Now, Craig...
...I was proud of you tonight.
You used your brain.
That's what I want you to do,
use your brain.
That's my boy.
Night, Mama.
Night, baby.
Dana.
Hello?
Why you can't call nobody back?
Which one of your hoes
has somebody shooting at you?
See, I don't know why I waste my time
on your old stupid ass anyway.
I don't know either.
It's over.
Bitch!
Yeah, I got your money.
I don't appreciate you sending
your punk-ass, bust-ass...
...Jheri-curl-ass friends
to shoot at me and my homey.
They like to got dealt with.
Don't be calling here
like you some straight up G...
...because I'll cut your balls off
and hand them to you, partner.
I had to warn you too many times
about my money, Smokey.
It's the principle of the whole thing.
It's principalities in this.
Well....
Yeah, hey, I got your money anyway.
And you sell that shit yourself next time.
Because I'm going to rehab.
I'm through with this shit.
I was just bullshitting.
And you know this, man.